<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tarek Sheikh AL-Shbab</title>
    <description>Tarek, Bachelor’s degree in Management information systems, Passionate about Business, Data and Entrepreneurship. A Web Science master’s degree student.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 14:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 14:04:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spike - makes AI accessible for all businesses, governments and other enterprises</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Spike it’s an online platform that makes AI accessible for all businesses, governments and other enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every business needs artificial intelligence.&lt;br /&gt;
But not every business has the capability to build, maintain, and generate value from AI in-house.&lt;br /&gt;
Spike makes AI accessible for all businesses, governments and other enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By harnessing the power of your data to assist – not displace – humans at work, we improve business efficiency and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And all of that will be provided with:&lt;br /&gt;
1- Data warehouse&lt;br /&gt;
2- Interactive Analytics&lt;br /&gt;
3- Prediction and forecasting report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With:&lt;br /&gt;
* No AI or machine learning experience required.&lt;br /&gt;
* No infrastructure needed.&lt;br /&gt;
* Supporting the MENA region and we are less expensive for other solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spike was my graduation project too from Business Administration/ Management Information Technology department of the Arab International University in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the Degree of Bachelor of Business Administration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More about Spike down below, youtube ads, pitch deck of Spike, graduation project report:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/v=RltD80HK0io&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/e7PYTQcfNYnPqI&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:5px&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/tarepsh/spike-pitch-deck&quot; title=&quot;Spike - pitch deck&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Spike - pitch deck&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/tarepsh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tarek Sheikh AL-Shbab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/H0N667FgZAbP2&quot; width=&quot;668&quot; height=&quot;714&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:5px&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/tarepsh/spike-report-for-degree-of-bachelor-of-business-administrationmanagement-information-technology&quot; title=&quot;Spike - Report for Degree of Bachelor of Business Administration/Management Information Technology&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Spike - Report for Degree of Bachelor of Business Administration/Management Information Technology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/tarepsh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tarek Sheikh AL-Shbab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2023/06/21/spike/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2023/06/21/spike/</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Startups</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AUB AI for Accessibility Hackathon - MLTK</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The AUB AI for Accessibility Hackathon is an exciting event that brings together talented individuals and fosters the development of the innovative entrepreneurship community in the field of Artificial Intelligence. With a strong focus on social inclusiveness, this hackathon aims to provide solutions for people with disabilities, particularly those falling under assistive technologies or physical aids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a passionate advocate for leveraging technology to improve the lives of individuals with disabilities, I participated in the AUB AI for Accessibility Hackathon with great enthusiasm. Recognizing the immense potential of AI in addressing accessibility challenges, I joined a team of like-minded individuals who shared a common goal of creating impactful solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the hackathon, our team focused on developing a non-standard speech-to-text tool with Arabic language support. Our vision was to build a Software as a Service (SAAS) solution that could be easily integrated into various applications, allowing developers to implement our tool and make a positive difference in the lives of people with speech impairments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core idea behind our solution was to utilize AI algorithms to optimize voice recordings in Arabic and other languages, transforming non-standard speech into standard speech. By doing so, we aimed to enhance the accuracy and user experience of speech-to-text tools, making it easier for individuals with speech impairments to express themselves effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By participating in the AUB AI for Accessibility Hackathon, we had the opportunity to collaborate with experienced mentors, attend workshops, and receive valuable feedback on our proposed solution. The hackathon not only provided us with a platform to showcase our innovative ideas but also encouraged us to think critically about the needs of individuals with disabilities and explore how AI can address those needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, we plan to continue refining our solution and exploring avenues for its implementation in real-world scenarios. We believe that by providing developers with access to our SAAS tool and promoting its integration into various applications, we can create a more inclusive and accessible world for individuals with speech impairments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AUB AI for Accessibility Hackathon served as an inspiring platform for individuals passionate about harnessing the power of AI to address accessibility challenges. By participating in this hackathon, I had the privilege of collaborating with a talented team, refining our proposed solution, and envisioning a future where technology plays a transformative role in improving the lives of individuals with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team member:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/louayaz/&quot;&gt;Louay Abo Al-Zahab&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/kinana-rimawi/&quot;&gt;Kinana Al-Rimawi&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/malaztamim/&quot;&gt;Malaz Tamim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check our slides down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vTZJc9_5Q6GgoU_fJaSVsJ1JgwRqxxIT1fesSIdIzXP-CoQWR9qXgdIfj8mJJh2jQ/embed?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=3000&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;569&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2021/07/05/aub-ai-for-accessibility-hackathon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2021/07/05/aub-ai-for-accessibility-hackathon/</guid>
        
        <category>Startups</category>
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Automating Data Processing and Quality Assurance with Python and Dataiku for +2M Monthly Distribution Items</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Automated the collection, processing, analysis, visualization, and sharing of data from over 100 warehouses and 1 million distributions of items for more than 3.5 million beneficiaries in Syria, using Dataiku and Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that this is a high-level overview of your code. You can check more about from here: 
[“https://github.com/Syrian-Arab-Red-Crescent-SARC/Dataiku-auto-warehousing-and-distribution/blob/master/recipes/compute_test.py”]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/v=epRLY7Npf9Q&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/MAIsiD18fUBTxx&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:5px&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/tarepsh/sarc-data-wearhouse-automated-the-collection-and-process-monthly-data-for-100-sarc-warehouses-2m-distribution-items&quot; title=&quot;SARC Data Wearhouse - Automated the collection and process monthly data for +100 SARC warehouses &amp;amp; +2M distribution items&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SARC Data Wearhouse - Automated the collection and process monthly data for +100 SARC warehouses &amp;amp; +2M distribution items&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/tarepsh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tarek Sheikh AL-Shbab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2021/05/02/sarc-data-wearhouse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2021/05/02/sarc-data-wearhouse/</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WRO Costa Rica 2017 - Latakia 2030</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-wro-open-category-what-is-wro&quot;&gt;What is WRO Open Category? what is WRO?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World Robot Olympiad (WRO) is a global robotics competition for young people. The World Robot Olympiad competition uses Lego Mindstorms manufactured by LEGO Education. First held in 2004 in Singapore, it now attracts more than 26,000 teams from more than 65 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Category is a project based competition. Students create their own intelligent robotics solution relating to the current theme of the season. Teams will present their project and their robot model to a group of judges on the competition day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;latakia-2030&quot;&gt;Latakia 2030&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is a simulation of our vision for Syria in 2030 to be a smart country that uses the latest technology, green building methods, clean energy, data mining, image processing, visual reality, agreement reality, machine learning, computer vision, and more advanced technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we chose is the best place to start is Lattakia City in 2030 because of the rishi history and great geographic location that have a sea, mountains, and living city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/p3rBSB9RmV4&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/7c8YY6xVouGbqX&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:5px&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/tarepsh/wro-costa-rica-2017-latakia-2030-syria-report&quot; title=&quot;WRO Costa Rica 2017 – Latakia 2030 - Syria - Report &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WRO Costa Rica 2017 – Latakia 2030 - Syria - Report &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/tarepsh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tarek Sheikh AL-Shbab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2020/06/22/wro-costa-rica-2017-latakia-2030/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020/06/22/wro-costa-rica-2017-latakia-2030/</guid>
        
        <category>Robotics</category>
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Syria Arduino Day 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;World Arduino Day has been observed in more than 100 countries around the world, on March 16th every year. All sides interested, including educational institutions, organizations or hobbyists celebrate the even, highlight the Arduino circuits and its various applications and focus on the open-source culture and its importance in community development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World Arduino Day was organized at ASPU (Al-Sham Private University) theater with the participation of the Mechatronics Club at the Syrian Computer Society, the Robotics Club at the Faculty of Informatics at the University of Damascus and the Voluntary Ambition Team from the Faculty of Computer and Automation Engineering at Damascus University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this event was co-organize with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/alia-hamwi/&quot;&gt;Alia Hamwi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/louayaz/&quot;&gt;Louay Abo Al-Zahb&lt;/a&gt; and sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aspu.edu.sy/en/home&quot;&gt;Al-Sham Private University&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scs.org.sy/&quot;&gt;Syrian Computer Society&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/in-post/Syria-Arduino-Day-2019-AGENDA-page-001-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/v=EvZL8lNufP8&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aspu.edu.sy/en/news/31-yom-alardoyno-alaaalmy-fy-aspu&quot;&gt;http://www.aspu.edu.sy/en/news/31-yom-alardoyno-alaaalmy-fy-aspu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2020/06/22/syria-arduino-day-2019/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020/06/22/syria-arduino-day-2019/</guid>
        
        <category>Robotics</category>
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First-ever Startup Weekend event in Syria</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/in-post/download.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imperialism, ideology, and war are not historically unique developments in a city that predates human record. After ten millennia, there is very little that the city of Damascus has not experienced. A Startup Weekend; however, is one such event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 18, 2014, the international community will gain its first introscopic look into the entrepreneurial community of Damascus, the capital city of civil-war-laden Syria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 54-hour event will measure public interest in Startup technologies within Damascus, and will reward a winner with access to venture funding and publicity. The three-day event, will be preceded by a “bootcamp“ for participants, and will include a cast of international entrepreneurs are scheduled to attend online….. for more you can read one of below article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/startup-weekend-damascus\_b\_4782634&quot;&gt;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/startup-weekend-damascus_b_4782634&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wamda.com/2014/02/first-startup-weekend-in-damascus-an-active-environment-despite-the-crisis&quot;&gt;http://www.wamda.com/2014/02/first-startup-weekend-in-damascus-an-active-environment-despite-the-crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arabnet.me/english/editorials/events/damascus-to-host-its-first-startup-weekend-in-february&quot;&gt;https://www.arabnet.me/english/editorials/events/damascus-to-host-its-first-startup-weekend-in-february&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://communities.techstars.com/syria/damascus/blog/content/startup-weekend/startup-weekend-damascus-entrepreneurship-war-zone&quot;&gt;http://communities.techstars.com/syria/damascus/blog/content/startup-weekend/startup-weekend-damascus-entrepreneurship-war-zone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2020/06/22/startup-weekend/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020/06/22/startup-weekend/</guid>
        
        <category>Startups</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Robotics in Syria Report - 2017/2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This report highlights the experiences and needs of Syrian Robotics community in the country and shows other events, competitions, and activities of other countries around the world in goal to support robotic culture in this country. This report shows how we can implement or simulate this solution inside the Syrian community. This report shows a very close view of the author. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study aims to present policy and programme recommendations for use by governments, international NGOs, donors and other educational institutions, with the ultimate goal of helping youths get access to these kinds of sciences and activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analysis, results, and recommendations in this report represent the opinions of the author and are not necessarily representative of the position of the reviewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can check the report down below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/gOE1WlMiHLvqP8&quot; width=&quot;668&quot; height=&quot;714&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:5px&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/tarepsh/robotics-in-syria-report-20172018&quot; title=&quot;Robotics in Syria Report – 2017/2018&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Robotics in Syria Report – 2017/2018&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/tarepsh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tarek Sheikh AL-Shbab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2020/06/22/robotics-in-syria-report/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020/06/22/robotics-in-syria-report/</guid>
        
        <category>Robotics</category>
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MIT Global Entrepreneurship Bootcamp – Class 3</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-mit-global-entrepreneurship-bootcamp&quot;&gt;What is MIT Global Entrepreneurship Bootcamp?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bootcamp will be the most intense education experience of your life.&lt;br /&gt;
Throughout the program, Bootcampers learn and practice a variety of new skills related to entrepreneurship and innovation, both from MIT faculty, MIT coaches, and guest speakers as well as through their experiences in project teams. Each Bootcamper has the opportunity to be CEO, leading the team through its project work for a day. In one week, the Bootcamp provides participants many experiences most entrepreneurs and innovators face in the first 2-3 years of a new venture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/v=u6\_jdJ7YRXM&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-class-class-3---mit-global-entrepreneurship-bootcamp-seoul&quot;&gt;My class Class 3 - MIT Global Entrepreneurship Bootcamp, Seoul&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/v=0ovIQeVqEQc&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bootcamp.mit.edu/tarekalshbab/&quot;&gt;https://bootcamp.mit.edu/tarekalshbab/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2020/06/22/mit-global-entrepreneurship-bootcamp-class-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020/06/22/mit-global-entrepreneurship-bootcamp-class-3/</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Co-Organize National Competition - World Robot Olympiad WRO - Syria 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/in-post/WRO-2018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World Robot Olympiad (WRO) is a global robotics competition for young people. The World Robot Olympiad competition uses Lego Mindstorms manufactured by LEGO Education. First held in 2004 in Singapore, it now attracts more than 26,000 teams from more than 65 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Competition for Syria with more than 75 teams, 25 judges, 30 volunteers, 400 robotics match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This competition was sponsor by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scs.org.sy/&quot;&gt;Syrian Computer Society&lt;/a&gt; and co-organizer with Mr. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/waseem-saad-1924a043/&quot;&gt;Wassem Saad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e\_3PVwMx8-c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/v=e\_3PVwMx8-c&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/3jgyKTVG34Jb4&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:5px&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/tarepsh/national-competition-world-robot-olympiad-wro-syria-2018&quot; title=&quot;National Competition - World Robot Olympiad WRO - Syria 2018&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;National Competition - World Robot Olympiad WRO - Syria 2018&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/tarepsh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tarek Sheikh AL-Shbab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2020/06/22/wro-syria-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020/06/22/wro-syria-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>Robotics</category>
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet TOEBI your composting robot </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/in-post/IMG-20161024-WA0005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;toebi-makers---a-robot-that-makes-compost-for-us-with-a-mobile-app&quot;&gt;TOEBI Makers - A robot that makes compost for us with a mobile app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to share an exciting chapter of my life that revolves around my participation in the World Robot Olympiad (WRO) India. This international robotics competition brought together young minds from different corners of the country, igniting a passion for technology, innovation, and teamwork. Join me as I take you through my incredible journey of joining and preparing for the WRO India competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-wro-open-category-what-is-wro&quot;&gt;What is WRO Open Category? what is WRO?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World Robot Olympiad (WRO) is a global robotics competition for young people. The World Robot Olympiad competition uses Lego Mindstorms manufactured by LEGO Education. First held in 2004 in Singapore, it now attracts more than 26,000 teams from more than 65 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Category is a project based competition. Students create their own intelligent robotics solution relating to the current theme of the season. Teams will present their project and their robot model to a group of judges on the competition day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-the-spark-of-interest&quot;&gt;1. The Spark of Interest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I can remember, I’ve been fascinated by robotics. The idea of creating intelligent machines that can interact with the world around us always seemed like a magical realm waiting to be explored. So, when I stumbled upon the World Robot Olympiad, it felt like the perfect platform to turn my passion into reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-assembling-the-team&quot;&gt;2. Assembling the Team&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early stages, I shared my enthusiasm with like-minded friends who shared my interest in robotics. Together, we formed a team of three determined individuals, eager to take on the challenges that awaited us. Our diverse skill sets and complementary strengths laid the foundation for a successful collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-choosing-the-theme&quot;&gt;3. Choosing the Theme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each year, the WRO presents a unique theme to challenge participants’ creativity and problem-solving abilities. We eagerly awaited the theme announcement, and when it finally arrived, it centered around sustainability and the environment. Excitement filled our hearts as we brainstormed ideas and contemplated how our robot could contribute to a greener future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-designing-and-building&quot;&gt;4. Designing and Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the theme in mind, we began the process of designing our robot. We researched different mechanisms, explored various sensors and actuators, and sketched countless prototypes on paper. It was a thrilling experience to witness our ideas slowly take shape in the physical world. Hours turned into days as we tirelessly soldered, assembled, and fine-tuned our creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-programming-the-intelligence&quot;&gt;5. Programming the Intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building the physical robot was just the first step; we needed to breathe life into it through programming. We chose a programming language that allowed us to write complex algorithms and create autonomous behaviors for our robot. The code became the bridge between our imagination and the actions our robot would perform during the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-testing-and-iteration&quot;&gt;6. Testing and Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the competition date drew closer, we subjected our robot to rigorous testing and iteration. We fine-tuned its movements, optimized the algorithms, and eliminated any weaknesses we discovered along the way. It was a challenging process, but we understood that the key to success lay in perseverance and continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-competing-at-wro-india&quot;&gt;7. Competing at WRO India&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the day arrived when we showcased our robot at the WRO India competition. The atmosphere was electrifying, filled with the buzzing energy of participants from all over the country. We exchanged ideas, made new friends, and marveled at the incredible innovations others had brought to the table. It was an enriching experience that broadened our horizons and expanded our understanding of robotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-the-thrill-of-achievement&quot;&gt;8. The Thrill of Achievement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After months of hard work and dedication, our efforts bore fruit. We not only received recognition for our robot’s performance but also gained invaluable experiences and skills. The sense of achievement was overwhelming, knowing that our determination and teamwork had paid off. It was a moment I will cherish forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participating in the World Robot Olympiad India was an exhilarating journey that fueled my passion for robotics. It was not just about winning or losing; it was about pushing boundaries, embracing challenges, and fostering a love for technology and innovation. The WRO India experience has shaped me into a more confident and creative individual, ready to take on future&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more in this video and the full report down below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/v=4sfCTQXxCPw&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/cs0KJMmORyGxS4&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:5px&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/tarepsh/toebi-makers-wro-india-2016-open-category-syria-reportupdate1&quot; title=&quot;Toebi makers wro india 2016 - open category - syria - report-update1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Toebi makers wro india 2016 - open category - syria - report-update1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/tarepsh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tarek Sheikh AL-Shbab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2020/06/22/wro-india-2016-toebi-makers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020/06/22/wro-india-2016-toebi-makers/</guid>
        
        <category>Robotics</category>
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
